[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Which type of data Hadoop can deal with is",
    "answers": [
      "Structured",
      "Semi structured",
      "Unstructured",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Which statement is false about Hadoop:",
    "answers": [
      " It runs with commodity hardware",
      "It is a part of the Apache project sponsored by the ASF",
      "It is best for real-time streaming of data",
      "It can handle any type of data"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "It is best for real-time streaming of data"
  },

  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which of the following is component of Hadoop?",
    "answers": ["YARN", " HDFS", " MapReduce", "All of the above"],
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Hadoop Framework is written in",
    "answers": ["Python", "C++", "Java", "Scala"],
    "correctAnswer": "Java"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Which of the following is true about Hadoop?",
    "answers": [
      "Hadoop MapReduce processes the data at very low latency",
      " Hadoop can't handle structured data",
      "Hadoop is schema-less  we don't need to define a schema before writing the data",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Hadoop is schema-less we don't need to define a schema before writing the data"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which one of the following is false about Hadoop?",
    "answers": [
      "It is a distributed framework",
      " The main algorithm used in Hadoop is Map Reduce",
      "Hadoop can work with commodity hardware",
      " All are true"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": " All are true"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct statement:",
    "answers": [
      "Data locality means moving computation to data instead of data to computation",
      "Data locality means moving data to computation instead of computation to data",
      "Both the above",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Data locality means moving computation to data instead of data to computation"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which of the following property gets configured on mapred-site.xml ?",
    "answers": [
      " Replication factor",
      " Java Environment variables",
      "Directory names to store hdfs files",
      "Which framework to use with MapReduce jobs"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Which framework to use with MapReduce jobs"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which of the following is the daemon of Hadoop?",
    "answers": [" NameNode", " Node manager", "DataNode", " All of the above "],

    "correctAnswer": " All of the above"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which of the below component deals with ingesting streaming data into Hadoop?",
    "answers": ["Flume", "Oozie", " Hive", "Kafka"],
    "correctAnswer": " Flume"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Apache Hadoop achieves reliability by replicating the data across multiple hosts, and hence does not require ______ storage on hosts.",
    "answers": ["Filesystem", "RAID", "Local FS", "Operating system"],
    "correctAnswer": " RAID"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Which of the following platforms does Apache Hadoop run on ?",
    "answers": ["Bare metal", " Unix-like", "Cross-platform", "Debian"],
    "correctAnswer": "Cross-platform"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Hadoop works in",
    "answers": [" worker/slave fashion", "master slave fashion"],
    "correctAnswer": "master slave fashion"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "What license is Apache Hadoop distributed under?",
    "answers": [
      " Apache License 2.0",
      "Shareware",
      "Mozilla Public License",
      "Commercial"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Apache License 2.0"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "The archive file created in Hadoop has the extension of ",

    "answers": [".hrh", ".har", " .hrc", ".hrar"],
    "correctAnswer": ".hrar"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Which of the following provides a real-time stream processing system",
    "answers": [" Hive", "Solr", "Tez", " Spark"],
    "correctAnswer": " Spark"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "All the files in a directory in HDFS can be merged together using which of the following?",
    "answers": ["put merge", "get merge", "remerge", "merge all"],
    "correctAnswer": "get merge"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Which of the following is true about Hadoop?",
    "answers": [
      "HDFS Master (namenode) is the single point of failure",
      " We cannot edit a file once written in HDFS"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": " We cannot edit a file once written in HDFS"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Can multiple clients write into an HDFS file concurrently?",
    "answers": ["Yes", "No"],
    "correctAnswer": "No"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Checkpoint node download the FsImage and EditLogs from the NameNode & then merge them & store the modified FsImage:",
    "answers": ["Into persistent storage", "Back to the active NameNode"],
    "correctAnswer": " Back to the active NameNode"
  }
]
